嘿
Hey there
欢迎回到这个ASP.NET Core视频系列
welcome back to this ASP.NET Core videos series
我叫Jeff Fritz，我是jon galloway，
my name is Jeff Fritz I'm jon galloway,
你知道Jon，我们花了很多时间写代码
And you know what Jon, we've spent lot of time writing code
写入一些到Razor模板的HTML或Razor页面
writing some HTML in to Razor templates or razor pages.
这是我要写的一些代码。
and that's lot of code that I've to write.
如果我想要，重用其中的一些呢？
What if I want to do, re-use some of that?
是的，你知道，让我告诉你
Yeah, you know, let me tell you
最近我遇到了这个问题
recently I ran into this where I was working on
.NET基金会网站
the .NET foundation website
哦，好的。
Oh! OK.
主页的索引视图有很多信息
and the index view for the homepage there's a lot of information there
有各种各样的东西，有些东西是像一个小的新闻视图。
There's all kinds of stuff and some parts of it are things like a little News view.
你知道，最近的博客文章列表。
You know, a little list of recent blogs posts.
其中的一些部分令人令人沮丧的
and some parts of it are things there are some frustrating things with this
一个是，我的列表很长
One is， My view is huge.
我在滚动，滚动滚动，才能得到它
Times are I'm scrolling, scrolling scrolling to get to it
另一个问题——我可以把它分解，但这并不能解决问题。
Another prob-- and I can break it apart with partials, but it just kind of moves a problem, It doesn't really fix things.
另一件事是，我想要组件化，这样我就可以像你说的那样重复使用了。
another thing is， I want to componentize,，so I can reuse like you said.
我也不想要我的控制器
and I also don't want my controllers
或者我的页面代码必须返回各种各样的复杂的模型。
or my page code-behinds to have to return to have to return really complex models that have all kinds of.
这里是我的列表，这里是我的博客列表。如果我想在这个网站的其他地方实现它
I've all kind of-- here is my list in the here is my list of bloggers here is my--
and then if I want to  implement it somewhere else on this site.
这是一种重复的过程。
It kind of do that all over again.
是的
yes
这很困难，好的，
that's difficult yeah,  Ok,
那么解决这个问题的办法是什么呢？
so what's the solution for that?
所以我们谈到了这一点，，我认为，我认为它已经找到了一种贯穿整个列表——
Well, so we talked about this and  I thought it was find kind of running through the list with a--
你知道，我们正在谈论可以做一部分，回过来说，这有个子行为
you know, we're talking about like well we could do partial as we could do-- you know back we-- there is a child actions
MVC可用的子行为
which are available child actions work for them for mvc
有哪些子行为你可以放进控制器
and with a child action you can  put inside a controller， you can say,
你知道的只有部分视图会被这个控制器返回。
this is just you know for a partial view that's going to be return by this controller.
但问题是，它仍然直接与控制器联系在一起，
But the problem there it's still tied directly to controller,
对的
right
然后你提到标签助手，标签助手是一个很好的解决方案
And then you mention tag helpers,and tag helpers is a nice solution
我可以——一个标签助手可以——现在我可以创建一个漂亮的小标记
I can-- a tag helper can-- now I can create a nice little markup
我可以说，把这个写出来。
and I can say, write this thing out.
标签助手的问题是我失去了Razor格式。
the problem kind of with a the tag helper is I lose a Razor formatting.
好的，
okay,
把你所有的代码，所有的在C#（代码）中格式
get to write all your code, all your formatting in C#.
是的
yeah
用C#,编写标签助手
A tag helper is written in C#,
所以我把字符串格式化成HTML。
and so I am formatting strings into HTML.
那不漂亮！
That's not beautiful!
没有。
No.
这里的解决方案是视图组件。
So the solution here is view component.
好的，
ok,
视图组件非常酷，因为它允许我做一个小的组件，它是独立的。
A view component is really cool,because it allows me to make a small little component. its stand alone.
它不像我在页面或MVC中使用的整个模型绑定那样。
it doesn't do the whole model binding kind of thing that I would use in.in pages or MVC.
但它是某种东西，我可以直接进入任何视图
But it is something， I can just drop into any view
它自己工作。
it works all by itself.
它的好处是他只是一个简单的类，
and the nice thing with it is there's a simple class,
所有依赖注入都有我所有的服务
and it has all the thing all dependency injection has all my services available
然后它就有了一个相关的razor模板。
And then it's all got an associated razor template.
太酷了！所以我体会到了在Razor的好处
Very cool!  So I get the benefits of working in Razor?
我告诉你，
I get you know,
很好，我可以在一个类中写出漂亮的组件，漂亮的代码。
nice I can write nice component, nice code in a class.
是的！把它扔到永远的地方。酷！让我们看一看。
Yep！ drop it in where ever. Cool! Lets take a look.
是的
yeah
这里我举个例子
So here let me show an example
这是页面，我说的是
This is actually the page .I was talking about
这是一个主页例子，可以想象你网站的主页，有很多东西。
so this is an example homepage. an example homepage think of your home page of your website right and there's tons of different stuff.
我在这里滚动，这是左边的新闻列表，
And just I am scrolling through here is the list of news on the left,
右边的事件列表，还有一些其他的东西
list of the events on the right. So there's-- there some dropping things
如果我再往下看，我有一份最近的帖子列表。
If I look down at the bottom here again, I have got a list of recent posts.
这些都是
these are things that you know
你可以考虑其他一些事情。
you may consider some other things like.
在文档的这方面，这做的很好。
and on the doc's which are pretty good for this here.
他们列出了一些东西比如你可能有像云标签
They list some things like you may have something like a Tag cloud
或者购物车之类的东西，
or Shopping cart something where you know,
你想要把它放到一个页面里，这不仅仅是
you want to drop it into a page and it's not just
如果它只是一处标记，我只会使用PowerShell。
if its just a chunk of mark up I would use just a PowerShell.
当然
sure
但是如果你真的有一些——
but if it's something where if you've actually got some--
一些东西，像购物清单，
something to populate here like a Shopping cart list,
我真的认为以后会有一些代码来做这件事。
I really do think to make since to have  you know some code behind for it.
您需要服务器端代码进行交互。
you need that server side code to interact.
确实如此
it is Exactly
好的，
ok,
所以我要讲的是，我建议你去看文档，如果你去查看关于视图组件的信息
so what I'm going to be talking through here，  I refer you to the doc's， if you go to view components  is information about what a view component is and it talk's you through
构建一个视图组件实际上在后有一个完整的过程，
building a view componentand there is actually a whole walkthrough down at the end,
创建一个简单的视图组件。
creating a simple view component.
我实际上是在本地运行的。
so I've actually got that running locally.
让我们来看看代码是什么
and let's take a look at what the code
代码是怎样的
you know, how that code looks
这里
so here
这是一个标准视图
we've got actually here's this is a standard view
到下面，
down at the bottom,
我们已经在等待InvokeAsync，这是一个优先级列表
we've got this await  InvokeAsync,and it's a priority list
它说InvokeAsync组件
it says Component InvokeAsync.
所以，它以这种方式添加到这个视图组件。
So, it's pulling in this view Component that way.
如果我们看一下这个视图组件是如何定义的。
if we look at how that view component  is defined.
我们在这里
we have here
它是一个从视图组件继承的类
it's a class that inherits from view component
然后它就有了一个
and then it just has a
这里有一个GetItemsAsync。
here's it's got a GetItemsAsync.
所以，实际上——
So, really that's--
这里没有太多的代码。
there's not a lot of code here.
很好，它能
what's nice is it's able to
它可以在这里使用依赖注入，
it can use dependency injections here,
他们使用的是数据上下文
they're using a data context
我只是把它注射到那里
I'm just injecting it there
您还可以注入其他服务比如日志等。
you can also inject other services loggers etc.
当然
sure
所有这些都是返回一个列表。
and so all this is doing is returning a list.
这是async，所以它返回一个列表任务
So this is async so it's  returning a list of to do items as a task
然后在这个视图与它绑定。
then in the view for that it's just binding to it.
这是非常简单的绑定
so this is very simple binding.
这里我们有一个IEnumerable
here we've got an IEnumerable
我们只是绑定到一个IEnumerable
and we're just binding to that a IEnumerable list.
按照惯例
and there is some convention to this
这被称为default .cshtml
this is called default .cshtml
这是命名惯例， 这是你的components
And the kind of naming convention here is you have components
优先级列表，这是一个优先级列表视图组件，被称为default.cshtml
priority list is that the  it's a priority list view component and then it's called default.cshtml.
这和我们之前看到的文件夹非常相似
So this is very similar to have we have to views folder above
完全正确。
exactly.
这是在 Todo 控制器中的组件的视图。
and this is the views for a component being hosted inside of a to do control.
是的
yes
这个示例展示了多种宿主的方式，所以在这个列表中有一些不同的名字，
and this this sample shows multiple ways of hosting so there's actually some different names on the list,
但这个也是标准的default cshtml，你可以把它放在Share文件夹的或者specific 文件夹
but this one also is the standard would be default cshtml ，and you can put that either in shared or in the in the view specific one
在specific 控制器中
in the controller specific one ,controller specific exactly
这样我就可以使用相同的组件改变标记，根据不同的控制器需求
so this way I can use the same component  changed  the   markup  ，slightly  based on like different controllers needs
确切地说，我可以拥有一个标准的shared，然后在其他控制器中我可以进入并标记一点
exactly so I could have a shared one that's the standard one，  and then within other controllers  I can go in and mark that up a bit.
极好的
terrific
这是非常简单的
so this really is pretty straightforward now
因为这并不依赖于其他任何东西来显示（视图），我可以把它放到任何Razor视图中
because this isn't depending on anything else in order to display it I can drop it into any razor view
这是一种简单的注射方式
So the kind of simple way to inject this
简单的意思是默认的标准方式
simple meaning the default standard way as
我在调用Component.InvokeAsync
I'm doing Component.InvokeAsync
由于我没有模型绑定，我实际上是传递的参数
and then since I don't have model binding I'm actually passing and parameters here.
当然
sure
所以我说这是优先考虑的问题，这是显示是否完成。
so I'm saying this is the priority to take and this is whether show if they're done or not.
因为这是它的To-Do-List
because this is for it To-Do-List
这很好
this is okay
但我更喜欢用Taghelper来共享
but I actually prefer to share this using a Taghelper.
这是非常平滑的
this is pretty slick
因为Taghelpers清理了我们的灰色 razor-mark-up
because Taghelpers clean-up our gray razor-mark-up
他们有，对，这里他们有
They do, right. Here they've actually got
如果写vc：
If I do vc:
它自动地——就像视图组件一样自动变成了Taghelpers
it automatically--， like  view components  just automatically become  Taghelpers
好的
ok
所以它是内置的
so it's just built-in so
仅仅通过创建优先级列表
just by creating priority-list
vc优先级列表会自动生效，我的属性也自动绑定
vc priority list automatically works and on my properties here also automatically bound for me
所以我们在属性名和Taghelper的名称之间得到连字符
So we are getting the hyphen's between the names of our attributes and the name of of our Taghelper
因为这就是大写字母和名称之间的界限
because that's where the boundary is between the capitalized  word in the name
对我来说也是这样的
yeah also it does that conversion for me
所以
so
这很酷
so that's pretty cool
让我给你们举个例子来回顾一下我是如何使用这个的
let me show you an example that kind of to run back to how I uses this in mine so
我有一些标记要让它看起来像这样，这只是一个分段标记
I had some mark up for to look like this this is just kind of staging mark up
是的，但是我为什么要展示这些新闻，这是
right, but so  why I'm showing this news items  and this is
它使用bootstrap和使用Holder.js来显示不同类型的标记，比如缩略图。
it's using bootstrap and using Holder.js to show different kind of mark-up like thumbnails for them.
你知道，在bootstrap 中，有media-heading media-body pull-left ，所有这些东西。
you know so with bootstrap I've got media-heading media-body pull-left all that kind of stuff.
所以我不想在c#中生成这些
So I would not want to generate this all in C# but
但实际上有一些合理的代码
but there is actually some of reasonable manual code
这是拉取，这实际上是把它从IIS和东西中拉取出来。
There is pulling, this is actually pulling it from IIS feeds and stuff.
这里我有一个新闻订阅服务
So here I've got a NewsFeedService
我的新闻订阅服务是
and my NewsFeedService is it's
它运行的是这种后台任务，它实际上是使用一个联合
it's running this kind of background task, it's actually using a syndication
这些联合feed刚刚在.NET标准中提供，这是非常酷的。
These Syndication feed which just was made available in-- in .NET standard too recently which is very cool.
这是一种运行方式
So it's kind of running this
这是我得到的服务。
and this is a service that I've got.
然后，我已经加入了我的组件
So then I've-- I've got in my component
我可以注入这个。
I'm able to inject that.
所以我给我的服务注入了。
so I inject my service.
你知道，使用构造函数注入，所以我说
you know. using constructor injection so I said that
新闻服务，然后我就叫我的InvokeAsyn
newsService there and then and then I just call my InvokeAsyn
这个比我们要展示的要简单得多，
This one is simpler than that other one that you todo list we are showing,
它并不是在攻击数据库或者其他服务，而是在这里进行的艰苦工作。
it's not hitting a database or whatever the services doing the-- the hard work here.
这样你就知道了，获取feed的内容是在后台和服务背后进行的
So which just you know getting the feed the feed is cast behind the scenes and the service
它抓住了一个量，这个量实际上是在这里传递的
and it's grabbing a quantity and that quantity is being passed in here  actually
它是一个输入参数。
it's an input parameter.
it's an input parameter exactly.
所以我可以说这是我想要展示的多项新闻。
so I can say this is many news items I want to show.
然后我可以再看一遍，这是我实际上是我如何将它转换成Razor的
And then I can go over， and here is my actual this is how I converted it into razor.
所以我只是将绑定绑定到IEnumerable的新闻项
So I just binding am binding to  IEnumerable news items
然后我就用我的标准Razor
and then I'm just using my standard razor
你知道我在做一些事情，比如
you know I'm doing the few things items can take just like for instance
有多个与新闻提要相关联的URI，因为还有一个用于评论的RSS提要，诸如此类。
there is multiple URIs associated with the newsfeed, because there is also an RSS feed for comments and stuff like that.
我先把第一个加在这里，然后在这里，在描述中，我取了前50个字符。
So I'm garbing the first and then here and then here on the description I'm taking the first 50 characters.
对的
right
基本上这就是设置这个的全部内容。
so basically that's all that involved in setting that up.
这就是Razor模板
So,this is the Razor template
你的组件是视图正在呈现。
that your component is view is rendering with.
完全正确
exactly
好的
ok
然后，为了证明这是在
and so then that, just to kind of show whether that goes that is in
让我看看这里的新闻，
let me see NewsView right there,
这是Default.cshtml 好的。
it's a Default.cshtml, ok.
就是这样。
So that's it.
非常直接的，
So really pretty straight forward,
它解决了一个问题，当你遇到它的时候。是的，我的意思是，我希望我能打包。
it solves a problem that when you run into it. Yes I mean, I wish I can packages up.
我不想要
I don't want to have to
如果你发现自己来自一个页面或控制器返回一个非常复杂的模型
if you find yourself from a page or controller returning a very complex model
这里有一个列表，这里是这些和所有这些的列表。
that has here is a list of these and here is list of those and all that.
这是一个信号你可能想把它移到一个组件中
That's kind of sign that you may want to move that into a component
然后如果你有可重用的代码，你就想到复用
and then if you got re-usable code that you just want to reuse to your side.
是的
yeah
所以这是一个真正的结构
So this is in really a construct
像TagHelpers这样的视图结构
this is in the view structure like TagHelpers
他们想要捆绑到一个NuGet包并部署
they would want to bundle up into a NuGet package and deploy
因为我得到了那个Razor模板
Because of I got that razor template
我需要在我的应用程序中适当地部署。
that I need to deploy appropriately inside my application.
我认为这是一种更具体的应用，
exactly I think this is something where it's more kind of application specific,
可能有一些你知道的
there may be some you know
这是超级黑带层做某种路径提供了bla-bla-bla注入它
it's super black belt layer doing some kind of path provided bla-bla-bla to inject that
我认为标准的情况是清理我的标记，并在我的网站上通用的东西，添加到Razor模板里，
I think the standard case is just go through cleanup my markup and take  common things I'm going to use though my site ，put the razor template there,
把我的一个类，对，我的一个简单的类，然后在我的网站上重复使用
put my one class ，right ，my one simple class， and then just reuse from my site then
好极了。
terrific.
好了，就是这样。
all right so that's about it.
谢谢你的加入
thank you for joining us and
我们希望你能加入我们的下一个关于ASP.NET Core的视频。
we hope you join us  the next video on ASP.NET Core.